[Music]
hello everyone my name is Alexa driansky
I'm a senior software engineer with the
business Central team in Denmark today I
walk you through the latest improvements
in Coast adjustment for this
release Co adjustment is a crucial step
for ensuring accurate inventory
valuation in the system and we've been
working a lot to making it more
performant reliable and TR transparent
to users in this session I'll cover four
key
enhancements iterative adjustment for
better control over a large volume of
transactions forced adjustment to
correct issues when needed a self
diagnostics that makes the cost
adjustment more proactive in identifying
inefficiencies and highlighting them and
the course adjustment
traces for those who are interested in
internals how the cost adjustment is
doing behind the scene and to analyze
and
troubleshoot the adjustment process
let's dive in into each of these
features Coast adjustment for high uh
volume items for items with large amount
of transaction can be challenging and
the cost
adjustment might might not finish in one
run to make it possible to complete the
adjustment we now allow adjustment on a
period by period basis on a inventory
cost adjustment page which is a starting
point for every cost adjustment
investigation select an
item go to Coast adjustment entry
points select the date until which you
want to complete the adjustment and run
the adjust cost until valuation
date okay the same way you can adjust
specific production and assembly orders
with uh going to production orders to
adjust here and select the order or
orders then you need to adjust and
choose adjust course for selected
orders we've also introduced item by
item
commit which helps to reduce lock times
and to prevent full reruns if one of the
items fail to run the C adjustment with
this
mode use the report start the report
adjust go item entries with item by item
adjustment toggle
on sometimes especially on Old or highly
customized
environments you might spot an item
which is Market is adjusted but some of
its entries carry incorrect inaccurate
cost to force a rerun of course
adjustment for such entries you can use
these two actions on the item Ledger
entries page use an action mark for
adjustment for inbound entry so the
linked outbound entries will also be
recalculated and then on a new item
application entries page you can reset
outbound entries
updated with a name sake action to
reprocess outbow entries to ensure that
we be reconsidered in the next
adjustment to help you detect and uh
resolve inefficiencies business Central
now scans your setup and the coast
adjustment
data when you open the inventory Coast
adjustment tool you will see a
notification that the system has
detected potential issues in data or
settings that may affect the C
adjustment the action messages page
lists the warnings for the following
inefficiencies when the cost adjustment
is not running automatically and not
scheduled for manual or regular run if
the settings are not optimal for the
best
performance when inventory periods are
not in use and we strongly recommend
that everybody uses inventory period
many production assembly orders are not
adjusted many periods require
adjusted and loan processing times for
individual items or items that are
excluded from cast adjustment
exists and specific data the
discrepancies the Diagnostics happens
automatically but you can manually run a
scan any time using run checks action if
you need a break if you need to
pause you can snooze it Diagnostics up
to 30 days but you cannot disable it
completely Co adjustment can sometimes
take longer time than expected and the
reasons for that aren't always obvious
the cost adjustment Tracer tool will
help you analyze what's going on behind
the scene on the inventory course
adjustment tool you need to create a
select a batch set a timeout time up to
12 hours and run the course adjustment
with Trace toggle on while the course
adjustment is in process it records
events processed entries and the
information about these entries such as
items location variance production
assembly orders and the cost differences
calculated by the cost adjustment once
complete successfully or unsuccessfully
the log will be saved to database and
you can find this log under the trace
log
action and we strongly recommend that
you use that you switch to analys this
View mode because the log can be too
large to analyze it line by line
manually if I have problems with these
two items I can select
them use add bch here so so add these
two items to the batch open the item
batches we see two items that I've
selected I click the trace toggle here
and run the course adjustment for these
two
items the course adjustment is
complete and I can look at the trace log
this is was recorded for these two
items we introduced the inventory course
adjustment tool a year ago and since
then we have continued improving its
perform performance and features and
these new enhancements iterative
adjustments forced adjustment self
diagnostics and tracing will help you
gain more control improve efficiency and
troubleshoot issues
faster to stay updated on our progress
and new capabilities or provid us
feedback check out the resources listed
on that slide thank you and let's keep
the cost accurate and up to date
together